Klemen Slavič



I've been a professional full-stack developer since 2000. I've worked on numerous large-scale applications ranging from *mobile web development* to *backend database* and *cloud operations*. I prefer working with web technologies but I don't mind getting my hands dirty with other languages and platforms.

I am based in Ljubljana, Slovenia.

Core Skills

Frontend technologies

- React-like libraries (preact, React, etc.), Storybook, lit-html,
 Polymer, Web Components, WebWorkers, HTML5, CSS3, Houdini
 CSS, Backbone, jQuery
- Webpack, Vite, Rollup

Backend technologies

- MySQL, MSSQL, PostgreSQL, Redis, MongoDB, sqlite
- NodeJS, Deno, PHP, .NET/Mono

Miscellaneous

- ESNext, TypeScript, XAML, C#, RxJS, xState
- Unit and functional testing, mocking and E2E testing
- Author of and participant in various open source projects, currently Preact framework maintainer for Storybook

Language and education

Languages spoken

- Slovene, English (native)
- German, Croatian, Serbian (conversational)

Education

- *Gimnazija Vič*, Ljubljana high school graduated in top 5% nationally (2002)
- Fakulteta za Kemijo in kemijsko tehnologijo, University of Ljubljana studied Biochemistry (2002-2006)

Selected Work Experience

Technologies used

- TypeScript, Webpack, PostCSS
- WebGL, Canvas
- NodeJS, Ruby on Rails, Go
- MySQL, Redis, Memcache
- Docker, Kubernetes

Resource Guru

resourceguruapp.com

Senior Engineer, 2016 – current (remote; Reading UK, Ljubljana SI)

Resource Guru is a SaaS provider for scheduling people and resources with a novel clash management approach. The company is fully remote. During my time at the company, I worked on a number of notable upgrades and features:

- I rewrote the existing reporting feature to improve report generation responses by over 1,000× and wrote a custom XLSX pivot table generator that produces interactive tables typically in less than a second.
- I helped rewrite the visual scheduler that customers use to manage their schedules. This enabled users to simply scroll the timeline across time and resources and have data loaded reactively. The rewrite also let us deliver the application to mobile web users, something that was previously intractable with the legacy application.
- I introduced error capturing and reporting using Sentry, and introduced a modernized pipeline for frontend code using Babel, TypeScript, Webpack and PostCSS.
- I helped rewrite and enhance the existing customer-facing API from a *Ruby on Rails* implementation into a *NodeJS* codebase, which resulted in enabling previously intractable features (repeating and multi-resource bookings, timezone manipulation, etc.) with a worst-case response time improvement of over 1,000×. This also massively reduced table lockwait timeout errors that plagued the previous implementation.
- I led the introduction and implementation of Storybook and Chromatic as a design review and regression testing tool for components and features.

Technologies used

- CoffeeScript, Backbone, Browserify, Raphaël, Autoprefixer, Polymer, React, SASS/LESS
- NodeJS, PHP+Apache, nginx
- MySQL, MongoDB
- AWS, S3

Celtra

celtra.com

Lead Software Developer, 2011 – 2016 (Ljubljana SI, San Francisco CA)

I worked for Celtra in the *Ad Delivery Team*. My task was to develop, maintain and debug the rich media experience that powers ad display on various browsers and devices.

- I developed the core of the ad management interface to replace the previously unstructured application, which enabled rapid feature development.
- I developed and maintained the mobile ad runtime (a proprietary JavaScript library) that powered ad display on mobile and desktop web browsers, and inside native iOS and Android applications through a number of partner ad display SDKs.
- I worked in a distributed development environment that included developers in San Francisco, New York, London and Ljubljana.
- I spent considerable time researching browser internals and graphics glitches in order to produce a set of guidelines for developers. As part of this initiative, I held regular meetings with the teams to share these insights, which helped decrease the number of client-facing bugs by roughly 80%.
- I produced internal training, onboarding material and webcasts to document all aspects of the mobile runtime. Some of this material was subsequently used to assist clients with building their own custom solutions with my assistance.
- In addition to this core development role, I initiated and managed an experimental program that enabled fast iteration of ad format prototypes and produced a number of successful creative formats. This process also enabled us to develop production-ready formats in a matter of days rather than several weeks as was the case in the past.

Technologies used

- jQuery, Silverlight
- WinForms, WPF, ASP.NET MVC
- MSSQL
- Windows Azure
- Adobe Creative Suite, Microsoft Visual Studio

Kompas Xnet

kompas-xnet.si

Trainer and Developer, 2008 – 2011 (Ljubljana SI)

Before Celtra, I worked for Kompas Xnet, a Microsoft Partner company where I attained *Certified Trainer* status for *Microsoft* and *Adobe* products.

- I taught the official Microsoft curriculum to clients attending official developer courses and I developed and taught a custom course for Adobe products based on their official training books and materials.
- As a trainer, I also spent time on-site with clients that required training in web and .NET technologies.
- In my role as developer, I was tasked with frontend development for a series of client websites and desktop applications in *Silverlight*, *WPF*, and *Windows Forms*. Most notable was a rewrite and redesign of the website for BTC-City, the largest merchant center in Slovenia.
- I also filled the role of graphical designer and frontend developer for the company's printed products and the website itself.
- I worked closely with Microsoft developer evangelists and MVPs, developing with and presenting cutting-edge preview technology at the time (*Azure*, *Silverlight*, *WPF*, *ASP.NET MVC*).

Technologies used

- jQuery
- PHP5 + Symfony framework
- MySQL
- Apache

Tobonet, Httpool

httpool.com

Junior Systems Engineer, 2006, 2007 – 2008 (Ljubljana SI)

After *Tobonet* and its *ToboAds IP* was bought by *Httpool* in 2007, I rejoined the team to work on their advertising platform, working on the delivery backend, frontend code and the ad management interface built in *Symfony* using *jQuery* and some auxiliary plugins.

- I helped develop server-side code that matched ad views with keywords and worked on text feature extraction services. This included applicative research into various statistical and lexical methods known at the time.
- We wrote cross-browser ad display code that guaranteed compatibility with the 98th percentile of browsers at the time.
- I developed an internal Symfony plugin system that enabled translators to submit their work using inline editing within a running application instance.
- I helped port the code base from PHP4 to PHP5.

Noovo

Frontend Software Consultant, 2008 (Ljubljana SI)

During my time at *Httpool*, I was called into the sister company *Noovo* for a couple of months to assist with developing and optimizing their widget framework and load times on their social web application. We achieved that goal by creating a snappier and more responsive experience for users, dropping *Time to Interactive* from over 15 seconds down to 2 seconds or less.

Oxylus

Lead Developer, 2006 – 2007 (Ljubljana SI)

I developed a software package that helped managed the company's entry into Internet domain registration and management by automating the DNS registration procedure. I also worked on a client project coding and redesigning a website with CMS capability.

Education

High School

During high school I had the opportunity to participate in many STEM-related competitions (*chemistry*, *physics* and *mathematics*) and won several awards. As part of my STEM education, I also produced two research papers at the <u>Jožef Stefan Institute</u> on the topic of rare-earth magnets.

Outside of my academic work, I was very active in the school's debate community, eventually qualifying for the national debate team representing Slovenia at the *European* and *World Championships* in 2001 and 2002, respectively. In my fourth year, I also joined the school's *Theater Sports* troupe.

I graduated with 28 points, qualifying in the top 5% nationally.

University

I studied *Biochemistry* at *University of Ljubljana*, making it through the 3rd year before deciding to drop out. During this time, I was already working full-time on several software development-related projects which made me reconsider devoting any more time to furthering my studies. It still remains one of the most interesting topics personally, but has since fallen out of favour as my primary career choice.

Other Activities

I play keyboards, guitar and bass. I also like to draw comics and create procedural graphics using various web and 3D approaches. I sometimes play D&D games as a player, and more often than not, as the DM.

I dabble in Unity 3D and Blender.

I'm a K9 Rescue handler and I train my dogs for Mantrailing operations.